Register of the Fritz Machlup Papers, 1911-1983
Hoover Institution Archives
- NOTES, 1917-1983.
  - Economic development (Folder 11)
  - Economic growth (Folder 12-13)
  - Economic theory (Folder 14)
  - Economics (Folder 15)
  - Education (Folder 16)
  - Employment (Folder 17-18)
  - English language (Folder 78)
    - English for economists (Folder 1)
    - Misnomers (Folder 2)
    - Style rules in Fritz Machlup's writings (Folder 3)
  - Exploitation (Folder 4)
  - Fiscal policy (Folder 5)
  - Flexible exchange rates (Folder 6)
  - Gold (Folder 7)
  - Hayek, Friedrich A. von (Folder 8)
  - History (Folder 9)
  - Hollander, David H. (Folder 10)
  - Ideal types (Folder 11)
  - Inflation (Folder 12)
  - Information science (Folder 13)
  - International cartels (Folder 14)
  - International finance (Folder 15)
  - International monetary system (Folder 16-17)
  - International trade (Folder 18-22)
  - Keynes, John Maynard (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Klubertanz, George P. (Folder 2)
  - Knowledge industry (Folder 3-5)
  - Labor (Folder 6)
  - Liberalism (Folder 7)
  - Lindbeck, Assar (Folder 8)
  - Liquidity (Folder 9-11)
  - Marginal productivity (Folder 12)
  - Marx, Karl (Folder 13)
  - Methodology (Folder 14-17)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Monopoly (Folder 2)
  - National income (Folder 3)
  - Neutrality (Folder 4)
  - Patents (Folder 5-11)
  - Planning (Folder 12)
  - Profits (Folder 13)
  - Schutz, Alfred (Folder 14)
  - Science (Folder 15-16)
  - Sociology (Folder 17)
  - Tariffs (Folder 18)
  - Theories of the firm (Folder 19)
  - United States (Folder 20)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1911-1983.
  See also OFFICE OF ALIEN PROPERTY CUSTODIAN, INDEX CARD FILE, and OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - Unidentified fragments (Box 81, Folder 1-2)
  - "Approaches Used in Various Fields of Applied Economics," n.d. Holograph (Folder 3)
  - "Between Microeconomics and Macroeconomics: The Excluded Middle," n.d. Notes (Folder 4)
  - "Brief Bibliography of Monetary Theory of the Younger Austrian School," n.d. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - "Can a Liberal Defend Government Interventions to Restrict the Freedom of Business to Restrict Business? Questions by Fritz Machlup," n.d. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "The Case against International Cartels," n.d. Typescript (first page only) (Folder 7)
  - "Causes des Augmentations du Produit National: Temporaires, Sporadiques, ou Continues," n.d. Holograph (Folder 8)
  - "The Contribution of 'Technological Progress' to the Growth of the National Product," n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "A Critical Voice on the Singing Voice," n.d. Typescript on Joan Sutherland (Folder 10)
  - Discussion of Professor William's paper, n.d. Holograph (Folder 11)
  - "Economic Theory," n.d. Handwritten outline for projected book (Folder 12)
  - "Economics of Money and Banking," n.d. Typewritten first chapter (entitled "The Concept of Money") of a projected book (Folder 13)
  - "The Effects of Minimum Wage on Employment," n.d. Holograph (Folder 14)
  - "Eingliederung neuer Arbeiter durch Monopolpreissenkung," n.d. Holograph (Folder 15)
  - "Einige deutsche Fachausdrucke," n.d. Typewritten list of terms used in German economic discourse (Folder 16)
  - "Exclusive Rights: Are They Necessary as Incentives for Risky Investment?" n.d. Holograph (Folder 17)
  - "Fixed Costs, Once Again," n.d. Holograph (Folder 18)
  - "Freisetzung und Resorption," n.d. Holograph (Folder 19)
  - "General Equilibrium and Imperfect Competition: Are They Compatible?" n.d. Holograph and typescript (Folder 20)
  - "Geographic Price Structures, Competitive and Monopolistic," n.d. Notes and typescript (Folder 21)
  - "Glauben Sie an Wirtschaftsprognosen?" n.d. Holograph (Folder 22)
  - "The Government Should Get the Interest Rates Down!" n.d. Holograph (Folder 23)
  - "The Importance of Economic Theory," n.d. Typewritten outline (Folder 24)
  - "Industrial Price Policies and the Monopoly Problem" (with the assistance by John T. Dunlop), n.d. Typescript (Folder 25)
  - "The Inferiority of the Social Sciences," n.d. Typewritten abstract (Folder 26)
  - "International Aspects of Fascism and Communism," n.d. Notes (Folder 27)
  - "International Monetary Systems," n.d. Printed copy (Folder 28)
  - Introduction of Ludwig von Mises, Argentina, n.d. Typescript (Folder 29)
  - "Klassenkampf in Amerika," n.d. Printed copy (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - "Die Krise im internationalen Wahrungssystem und unternehmerische Verhaltensstrategie," n.d. Holograph (Folder 2)
  - "The Limits of Government Intervention in the Regulation of Labor Monopoly," n.d. Handwritten speech (Folder 3)
  - "Mathematical Economics and Econometrics: A Tale Told by an Idiot," n.d. Holograph (Folder 4)
  - "More Knowledge about More Knowledge," n.d. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - "A Note on Footnotes," n.d. Holograph (Folder 6)
  - "On Being Offended by the Objectively Inoffensive Customs," n.d. Typescript (Folder 7)
  - "On the Probability Value of Laws in the Physical and Social Sciences," n.d. Holograph (Folder 8)
  - "Overhead Cost and Unused Capacity," n.d. Projected book
    - Research material (Folder 9)
    - Notes (Folder 10)
    - Typewritten outline (Folder 11)
  - "The Political Arithmetic and Semantic of Economic Growth," n.d. Research material, notes, holograph, and typescript (Folder 12)
  - "Possible Reasons for Shorter Protection for Pharmaceutical Products," n.d. Holograph (Folder 13)
  - "Price Discrimination," n.d. Projected book
    - General. Includes typewritten outline (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Research material. Includes correspondence with Carl E. Wade (Folder 2-5)
    - Typescript (Folder 6-12)
  - "The Private Value of Patent Protection," n.d. Holograph (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - "The Problem of Adjustment" (with Peter B. Kenen), n.d. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - "Probleme, die ich naher ausfuhren mochte," n.d. Notes (Folder 3)
  - "Reparations: Why and How?" n.d. Holograph and typescript (Folder 4)
  - "Selektive Korrektivmasnahmen," n.d. Holograph (Folder 5)
  - Speech honoring Arthur O. Lovejoy on his birthday, n.d. Notes and holograph (Folder 6)
  - Speech on ideal types, Athens, Greece, n.d. Holograph (Folder 7)
  - "The Stability of the Foreign Exchange Market," n.d. Notes and typescript (Folder 8)
  - "Technokratie: Revolution der Techniker gegen die wirtschaftliche Vernunft," n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Die Theorie der Konjunkturbereitschaft," n.d. Handwritten speech (Folder 10)
  - "Theory: Its Role and Prestige in Society," n.d. Notes for speech (Folder 11)
  - "Unity of Science and Differences among Sciences," n.d. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "Veranderungen der Produktionsperiode und Storungen im Wirtschaftsablauf," n.d. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - "Wachstumsrate, Vollbeschaftigung, und Preisstabilitat," n.d. Holograph (Folder 14)
  - "What Is Meant by Methodology: A Selective Survey of the Literature," n.d. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - "What Methodologists Actually Wrote," n.d. Holograph (Folder 16)
  - "Who Coined the Term 'Duopoly'?" n.d. Research material, holograph (partial), and correspondence with Luigi Einaudi (Folder 17)
  - "A Workable and Practical Basis for the Solution of the Broad Problems of Post-War Employment in America," n.d. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "Der Umbau der Ferdinandsbrucke," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1911 April 8. Holograph and printed copy (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - "Die Goldkernwahrung: In geschichtlicher und theoretischer Behandlung," 1923. Doctoral dissertation
    - Typescript (Folder 2)
    - Reviews of printed copy (Die Goldkernwahrung, 1925) (Folder 3)
  - Die neuen Wahrungen in Europa, 1927. Printed copy and reviews (Folder 4)
  - Vorschlage fur eine wirtschaftliche und sichere Wahrung, 1927. Translation of David Ricardo, Proposals for an Economic and Secure Currency. Reviews (Folder 5)
  - Review of Leon Koppel, Grenznutzentheorie und Markismus, 1930? Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "The Critics of the Goldstandard," 1930s. Typescript (Folder 7)
  - "The Debt-Overhead Theory of Depression or What Is the Real Effect of Fixed Burden on Prices and Production in Depression?" 1930s. Handwritten speech (Folder 8)
  - "Devisenbeschrankungen in Osterreich," 1930s. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Dollars without Cents," 1930s. Handwritten speech (Folder 10)
  - "Kapitalflucht und ihre Wirkungen auf den Kapitalmarkt," 1930s. Speech, Frankfurter Gesellschaft fur Konjunkturforschung, Frankfurt, Germany. Clippings (Folder 11)
  - Notes on the history of the sale of Fritz Machlup's business, 1930s (Folder 12)
  - "On Empiricism," 1930s. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - Speech on credit control, 1930s. Handwritten speech (partial) (Folder 14)
  - "The Theory of Interest," 1930s. Handwritten speech (Folder 15)
  - "What Are the Right Foreign Exchange Rates?" 1930s. Handwritten speech (Folder 16)
  - Notes for speeches on political economy, 1930-1931 (Folder 17)
  - Borsenkredit, Industriekredit und Kapitalbildung, 1931
    - Typescript (partial) (Folder 18)
    - Reviews (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - English translation of a revised German version (The Stock Market Credit and Capital Formation), 1940. Review and correspondence with Wilford J. Eiteman (Folder 2)
  - "Sie wissen nicht was Inflation ist," 1932? Typescript (Folder 3)
  - Articles intended for the series "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1932-1934. Typewritten drafts for unidentified articles and/or never published (Folder 4)
  - "Wahrungspatriotismus: Ein Beitrag zur wirtschaftlichen Vernunft," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1932 February 18. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Alle wollen Hauser bauen," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1932 April 17. Typescript of answer to Mr. Sommerlatte's comments (Folder 6)
  - "The Liquidity of Short-Term Capital," Economica, 1932 August. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "Die Theorie der Kapitalflucht," Weltwirtschaftliches Archiv, 1932 October. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Der Dalai Lama wird verjagt," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1932 October 16. Printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "Industrialisierung, Autarkisierung, Arbeitslosigkeit" Mitteilungen des Verbandes osterreichischer Banken und Bankiers, 1932 December. Handwritten fragment (Folder 10)
  - "The Zeitschrift fur Nationalokonomie," 1933. Handwritten speech (Folder 11)
  - "Zur Frage der Ankurbelung durch Kreditpolitik," Zeitschrift fur Nationalokonomie, 1933. Review (Folder 12)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Anderer Lander Inflation," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1933 April 16. Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Ist das kein Widerspruch?" Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1933 June 4. Printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Kontrollierte Inflation?" Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1933 July 9. Printed copy (Folder 15)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Der Verkehrsruckgang ist zu gross," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1933 September 24. Printed copy (Folder 16)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Die Ergiebigkeit der Arbeit hangt davon ab," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1933 October 22. Printed copy (Folder 17)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Die Verschiebung der Kaufkraft," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1933 November 26. Printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "Die Professoren sind schuld," 1933 December 3. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Landwirtschaft und Industrie," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1933 December 24. Printed copy (Folder 20)
  - Fuhrer durch die Krisenpolitik, 1934
    - Typescript of notice sent to Jahrbucher fur Nationalokonomie und Statistik and cover letter (Folder 21)
    - Reviews (Folder 22)
    - French translation. Review (Folder 23)
  - Talk on the [Eugen von] Bohm-Bawerk theory in Professor Frank W. Taussig's class, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1934. Holograph (Folder 24)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Geschenk fur Silberbesitzer," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1934 January 21. Printed copy (Folder 25)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Das heilige Preisniveau," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1934 February 25. Printed copy (Folder 26)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Er verkauft zu billig," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1934 March 4. Printed copy (Folder 27)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Was ist eigentlich Deflation?" Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1934 March 25. Printed copy (Folder 28)
  - "Ergebnis meiner Umfrage uber einige 'begriffliche' Unklarheiten in der Kapitaltheorie," 1934 April? Typewritten report on an informal survey on the theory of capital. Includes circular letter sent to Gottfried Haberler, George N. Halm, Friedrich A. von Hayek, Jacob Marschak, Ludwig von Mises, and Richard von Strigl, with a list of five questions; Fritz Machlup's own answers, and those of Hayek, Marschak, and Mises; and a follow-up report, "Nachtragliche Bemerkungen zu meiner Umfrage uber eine 'begriffliche' Unklarheiten in der Kapitaltheorie," written after October 1934 (Folder 29)
  - "Zwei Minuten Volkswirtschaft: Ein tuchtiger Spekulant," Neues Wiener Tagblatt, 1934 May 27. Printed copy (Folder 30)
  - "Talk With Herbert Hoover, Palo Alto," 1934 June 16. Holograph notes (Folder 31)
  - "The Consumption of Capital in Austria," 1934 December 3. Speech, Boston Chapter, American Statistical Association, Boston, Massachusetts. Correspondence (Folder 32)
  - "On the Elasticity of Substitution between Labor and Capital," 1934 December 27. Speech, Econometric Society, Chicago, Illinois. Typescript and correspondence (Folder 33)
  - "The Older and the Younger Austrian Economists and Their Problems," 1935? Speech, Columbia University, New York City. Holograph (Folder 34)
  - "Wirtschaftspolitik?" 1935? Notes for a speech (Folder 35)
  - "The Commonsense of the Elasticity of Substitution," Review of Economic Studies, 1935 June. Printed copy (Folder 36)
  - "The Transfer Discussion in the Light of Recent Experience," 1935 November 11. Handwritten speech (Folder 37)
  - "Up-Hill Race: Leading and Trailing Nations in the World Recovery," 1936? Typescript (Folder 38)
  - "Why Bother with Methodology?" Economica, 1936. Proofs (Folder 39)
  - "Austria as the Pawn of Europe," 1936 February 12. Speech, Buffalo, New York. Holograph (Folder 40)
  - "Efficient Boom-Brakes," 1937? Typescript (Folder 41)
  - "Monopoly and Competition: A Classification of Market Positions," American Economic Review, 1937.
    See CORRESPONDENCE, Adolf Kozlik
  - "Are the Margin Regulations at Fault?" 1937 October. Correspondence (Folder 42)
  - "The Stock Exchange as a Gauge of Credit Policy and a Regulator of Investment," 1937 December 29. Paper, Round Table, The Influence of Security Market Regulation upon Fluctuations of Investment, American Economic Association. Typewritten abstract and correspondence with Ray Bert Westerfield (Folder 43)
  - "Political Situation in Austria," 1938? Handwritten speech (partial) (Folder 44)
  - Appearance, Buffalo Evening News Radio Station, Buffalo, New York, 1938 April. Correspondence (Folder 45)
  - Review of Richard von Strigl, Einfuhrung in die Grundlagen der Nationalokonomie, in American Economic Review, 1938 June. Typescript (Folder 46)
  - "The Practical Significance of the Theory of Monopolistic Competition," 1938 December. Paper, American Economic Association, Detroit, Michigan. Correspondence with Frederic B. Garver (Folder 47)
  - "Evaluation of the Practical Significance of the Theory of Monopolistic Competition," American Economic Review, 1939.
  - "The Theory of Foreign Exchange" (Parts I and II), Economica, 1939 and 1940. Printed copy and review (Folder 48)
  - "Social Order" (with Norman Thomas), 1939 June 27. Speech, Institute of International Relations, Mills College, Oakland, California. Correspondence with Joseph W. Conard (Folder 49)
  - "Our Buried Gold," 1940 August 7. KGO Radio talk. Notes and typescript (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - List of seven possible topics (for a speech?), 1941 October 19 (Folder 2)
  - "A Civil War Is On," 1941 November. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - Speech, Niagara Falls, New York, 1942 February 15. Correspondence (Folder 4)
  - "Competition, Pliopoly and Profit," Economica, 1942 February (Part I) and May (Part II). Printed copy (Folder 5)
  - International Trade and the National Income Multiplier, 1943. Notes, tables, reviews, and comments (Folder 6)
  - "Programs to Maintain Employment: The Basis of Social Security," 1944 January 10. Paper, National Conference on Social Security, Chamber of Commerce of the United States, Washington, D.C. Typescript and letter from Emerson P. Schmidt (Folder 7)
  - "A Discussion of International Cartels," 1944 June 24. Presentation, Economic and Financial Group, Council on Foreign Relations. Typescript (Folder 8)
  - Manuscript on unemployment, 1945? Partial typescript (Folder 9)
  - Financing American Prosperity, Paul T. Homan and Fritz Machlup, eds., 1945
    - General (Folder 10)
    - Typewritten statement for Twentieth Century Fund (Folder 11)
  - "The Nature of the International Cartel Problem," 1945 March 8. Speech, Columbia University, New York City. Typewritten synopsis (Folder 12)
  - "The Effects of Government Spending upon Employment," 1945 September 24. Handwritten and typewritten outline (Folder 13)
  - Letter to the editor (re Seymour E. Harris' review of Herman Finer, Road to Reaction), New York Times, 1945 December 13 (date written). Typescript (Folder 14)
  - "Government and Full Employment," 1946 May 22. Paper, National Conference of Social Work. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - "Some Aspects of Full Employment Policy," 1947? Typescript and correspondence with J. J. Gonzales-Gorrondona (Folder 16)
  - Review of Economic Research and the Development of Economic Science and Public Policy: Twelve Papers Presented at the Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Meeting of the National Bureau of Economic Research, in Journal of Political Economy, 1948. Typescript and correspondence with William H. Nicholls (Folder 17)
  - "What's Best for the Competitive Enterprise System?" 1948 December 10. Panel participation, Economic Institute on Delivered Pricing and the Future of American Business, Chamber of Commerce of the United States, Washington, D.C. Typescript and clipping (Folder 18)
  - Participation, American Economic Association, Cleveland, Ohio, 1948 December 29-30. Typescript
    - "The Inflationary Process" (comments on papers by Seymour E. Harris and Professor Lerner), December 29 (Folder 19)
    - "The Economics of Preparedness for War" (discussion), December 30 (Folder 20)
  - The Basing-Point System, 1949
    - Reviews (Folder 21)
    - Correspondence with and comments from Gardner Ackley, Fred E. Clark, William Johnson, James Lake, Mark Wehle, 1948-1955 (Folder 22)
  - Report on Grant No. 995 (1947) for "An Analysis of the Economics of the Patent System," American Philosophical Society, Year Book 1948, 1949. Typescript (Folder 23)
  - Review of Erich Schneider, Einfuhrung in die Wirtschaftstheorie, I. Teil: Theorie des Wirtschaftskreislaufs, in American Economic Review, 1949. Typescript and proofs (Folder 24)
  - Statement on small business objections on basing point legislation, particularly S. 1008, United States Congress, House of Representatives, Select Committee on Small Business, 1949 July 6. Notes, typescript, and printed copy (Folder 25)
  - "Three Concepts of the Balance of Payments," 1949 October 21. Paper, International Monetary Fund Seminar, Washington, D.C. Typewritten outline (Folder 26)
  - Discussion of Dr. Koopmans' remarks, Conference on Business Cycle Research, Universities-National Bureau Committee for Economic Research, 1949 November 28. Typescript (Folder 27)
  - "The Elasticity Argument for Foreign Exchange Restrictions," 1949 December 28. Remarks, International Trade Meeting, Econometric Society. Holograph and typewritten abstract (Folder 28)
  - "Elasticity Pessimism in International Trade," Economia internazionale, 1950. Typewritten abstract (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - "The Patent Controversy in the Nineteenth Century" (with Edith T. Penrose), Journal of Economic History, 1950
    - Research material and notes. Includes an essay by Edith T. Penrose (Folder 2)
    - Holograph (Folder 3)
    - Typescript (Folder 4)
  - Report on Grant No. 1085 (1948) for "An Analysis of the Economics of Patents and Copyrights," American Philosophical Society, Year Book 1949, 1950. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - "Three Concepts of the Balance of Payments and the So-Called Dollar Shortage," Economic Journal, 1950 March. Printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "The Unreal World of Theorists and Experimentalists," 1951. Typescript (in part holograph) (Folder 7)
  - "Equilibrium in International Trade," 1951 January 29-31 and February 1-2. Series of five speeches, Graduate Institute of International Studies, Geneva, Switzerland. Notes (Folder 8)
  - "A Check Up of the American Economy," 1951 March 28. Speech, The Phoenix Club, Baltimore, Maryland. Correspondence (Folder 9)
  - "Schumpeter's Economic Methodology," Review of Economics and Statistics, 1951 May. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "Model Analysis in Economics," 1951 August 18 -September 7. Workshop contribution, European Forum Alpbach 1951, Formprobleme: Strukturen und Modelle, Alpbach, Austria. Notes (Folder 11)
  - "Monopoly and the Problem of Economic Stability," 1951 September 7? Paper, Round Table on Monopoly and Competition and Their Regulation, International Economic Association, Talloires, France. Notes and typescript. (Folder 12)
    See also CORRESPONDENCE, Edward H. Chamberlin
  - "The Characteristics and Classifications of Oligopoly," Kyklos, 1952. Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - The Economics of Sellers' Competition, 1952
    - Reviews (Folder 14)
    - German translation. Reviews (Folder 15)
    - Italian translation. Review (Folder 16)
    - Japanese translation. Typewritten preface and correspondence with Keitaro Fukuda and Masahiro Hattori, 1963-1966 (Folder 17)
  - The Political Economy of Monopoly, 1952.
    See The Economics of Sellers' Competition, 1952
  - "Replies by Economists" in Monetary Policy and the Management of the Public Debt, United States Congress, Joint Committee on the Economic Report, Subcommittee on General Credit Control and Debt Management, 1952. Typescript. Includes printed copy of questions (Folder 18)
  - "Characteristics and Types of Price Discrimination," 1952 June 17-19. Paper, Conference on Business Concentration and Price Policy, Universities-National Bureau Committee for Economic Research, Princeton University, New Jersey. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "Deutschlands Ruckkehr zum Weltmarkt," 1953. Speech, Dusseldorf, Germany. Notes (Folder 20)
  - "Do Economists Know Anything?" American Scholar, 1953. Printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "Public Policy and Patent and Trademark Law," 1953 June 15. Paper, Antitrust Seminar, University of Chicago Law School, Illinois. Holograph and typescript (Folder 22)
  - Participation, "Trade, Aid, or What?" Summer seminar, Merrill Center for Economics, Southampton, New York, 1953 June 28 -August 21
    - General (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Notes
      - International trade (Folder 2-3)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 4)
    - Typescript entitled "Problems of Exchange Rates and Convertibility" (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Willard L. Thorp (Amherst College) (Folder 6)
  - "My Research and My Students," 1953 November. Holograph (Folder 7)
  - Participation, Round Table on Graduate Education in Economics, American Economic Association, 1953 December 29. Holograph (Folder 8)
  - Essays in International Trade and Capital Transfer, 1954.
    See CORRESPONDENCE, Oxford University Press
  - "Dollar Shortage and Disparities in the Growth of Productivity," Scottish Journal of Political Economy, 1954 October. Proofs and printed copy (Folder 9)
  - Notes, handwritten essays, and typewritten diary entries ("reports") on the Japanese language and on Japanese society and education, 1955 March-April. Includes clippings (Folder 10)